Welcome to this video series. In this
video series, we will be discussing
about a Microsoft agent framework.
Again, this is a open source framework
from Microsoft.
This is just not meant to build a
chatbot. But like you can also build a
chatbot decision-m workflows, autonomous
workflows using this particular
framework. Microsoft combined all of the
existing product and services into this
particular framework that includes
autogenic kernel Azure AE agent service.
So when you use the agent framework
essentially you will be using all of
these three product and services
together. You build using the agent
framework that can be deployed in your
local machine or in Azure. For instance
when you are building a workflow that
can run in your local machine when you
create a agent that can be hosted in the
Azure. So it does support both the
environment
and like again like this is completely
supported by Microsoft and I see that
lot of commits are happening in this
particular framework in the recent past.
So which means that when you using this
particular library or so if you come
back there is going to be a change. So
there is no guarantee that this
particular code will work forever. So
you have to adapt the changes right.
comes to the installation.
So it is a pretty simple installation
basically like I'm just going to use
Python though it does support a various
other languages. Uh I would prefer
Python for this particular purpose. So
you you have to create a a virtual
environment and activate the environment
and do the installation. So let me go to
the Visual Studio Code here. So like
what are the libraries that I'm using?
So if you see here these are all the
libraries that I'm using, right? it will
work on this particular library but
there is no guarantee that it will work
in the upcoming
so basically you have to make the code
changes accordingly
we'll see how do we create the agent
first we will start with the in-memory
agent in memory agent in the sense the
agent will be existing only in your
machine as soon as the execution it's
done there is not going to be anything
right means everything will be cleaned
up so if you look at this I'm loading
the environment variable so let's go to
the visual studio code and see. So if I
go to the ENV file, so some of these
information are needed. So the project
endpoint, deployment name, open API
endpoint and the like chart name, keys.
So some how do we get this information?
First we will see how do we get the
project endpoint. Again, navigate to the
portal here. If you go to the foundry
and open up your project, this is where
you will see the project endpoint. Just
copy this information.
uh and then like we need to have a model
deployment name model deployment name
again like if you just go to the model
so like this is what I have deployed I
have my deployment name it's a GPT4 mini
right and like open API endpoint so if
you just click on that if you click on
this deployment name uh here by like you
will see the open API uh project name as
well as its key so copy all of this
information populate your env file Now
let's go to the documentation. So if you
see here, I just import the class called
Azure OpenA chat client from this
particular package and like I am using
that particular class by passing all of
this information including the endpoint
and deployment name key and the vision
information. Finally I will make a call
uh to the method called create agent by
passing the instruction name of the
agent. Now we have the agent ready. we
can just run the agent. So here like I
just go in a loop and like get the use
input from the user and pass it to the
agent. So if you see here I just call it
agent run string by passing the input
from the user. Now let's go to the
visual studio code and run it. Execute
the code. Make sure like you are using
the easy login to log into your uh Azure
subscription. I'm not going to do it.
Let me skip that. So now let me go ahead
and clear this console.
And let me run the file here. So I just
make a call to the first program here.
So now it is going to create a uh
inmemory agent. So if we just go to the
port again, if I just see here, there is
not going to be any agent created
because it is inline inmemory agent. So
now let me go ahead and uh provide the
user input here. So let me ask what
return the response. So now the agent
responded back. Now let me quit. So this
is how we create a in-memory agent. So
basically like we will not create
anything in the Azure right. So this is
all will get executed in your local
machine. Now let's move forward. So in
this case instead of using the open GA
agent so if you see here like we we were
using open GA client right? So instead
of that I will be using uh Azure agent
client. Right? So what is the
difference? So the difference is that
again this is going to be a temporary uh
agent uh but then like it will create a
agent in the Azure and then like as soon
as the execution it's done that is going
to get deleted. So everything will be
same. So if you see here this time
around instead of passing the API uh key
open API key we are using the Azure CLA
credentials right. So there are quite a
few type of credentials that that is
supported but like for this particular
video series I will be using the CLA
credentials. So now with that again like
I'm I'm reading the project information
model deployment name from the ENV file
and like this agent client if you just
come over here this is also part of the
same library. So instead of importing
the Azure open gay chart client I just
imported this particular client this uh
this is again coming from Azure identity
library. So I will use that and then
like using which I will create a Azure
agent chart client by passing the
credentials and I call it is the same
kind of a method create agent name and
instructions are provided. Uh everything
else will be the same. We will be going
in a loop and reading the information
from the user passing it to the agent.
Call the uh run stream method and print
the value. Now let me go and play the
console again. Now let me go ahead and
call the function here. Now let me ask
the same question here. Now this time
around uh it took a while. The reason is
that if I just go back here, if you
refresh it here, you will see the
inmemory Azure agent got created, right?
But then like if I okay, let me ask one
more question here. What is the capital
of India? This time around the response
is going to be quick because like the
very first time when you do it, it is
going to create a agent and then like
pass it to the uh agent. Right now as we
already have the agent, it will just
reuse the agent and the subsequent
queries will be fast enough. Now let me
go ahead and quit. Now what will happen
is that as this is just a inignment. Let
me just come over here and do a refresh.
You will not see anything because like
as soon as the execution it's done that
will get destroyed. Now again like there
is also going to be a one another type.
Let me again clear the console. the
console. Now let me minimize this. So if
you see here this time around instead of
using uh instead of directly using the
Azure a chat client I'm using chart
agent right. So there are three layers.
First you will have your model and the
like you will have your agent client
then on top of that you will have your
chart agent.
Right? So the model it's nothing but
your LLM or open A right open a LLM LLM
and then like on top of that you will
have your Azure agent client and that
will cover the state thread
uh thread and and like you will have
your chart agent that that will provide
additional features like middleware
uh telemetry all this information right
so it's up to us uh we can easily as the
middle middle layer here right so we
don't need that we can use with the
chart agent we can directly use the llm
also but in most of the cases this is
the flow right so now if you see here I
did not create the llm one but then like
if you see closely here I'm passing the
deployment name the deployment name
behind the scenes it is just a model
right so the agent client will use the
model and the like the chart agent will
use the agent trade agent trade that's
how it works. So now with that let me go
ahead and run the program. If you see
the program it's as simple as that. So
in the previous program like we we just
created a agent of using this particular
object but then like now as we have this
particular class that will work as a
agent for us. Now rest of the program
will be seen. Now let me copy this. Now
let me run this program.
Let me ask uh the question here. So what
is the LLM and the likeum? What is the
capital of U India? Right. Let's
maximize this. Now let it complete.
Okay. Now let me ask the next question.
What is the capital of India? It just
responded. Now let me ask you this
question. So what is what was my first
question? Right. It is not going to
respond back properly because in the
sense like by default you will not get
all the features. You have to do the
configuration because like we are not
using any thread here. So even if you is
agent client with the Azure agent client
it is not going to respond back properly
right because there is a way to do that
like you need to have a thread and all
of those that we will come back in a
moment. Now let's talk about um stream
nonstream. So in these keys like again
like I will use the same uh kind of a
sample here uh Azure Agent client. I
just created a client here. Okay before
I do that let me exit from this
particular program. So now in this
particular program I just created a
Azure agent client
uh and if you see here u I just make a
call to run method right. So in the
previous videos we have we were using
run stream in this program we are using
run method. So now let's see like what
is the difference here. So if I just
come over here run as a nonstream. If
you if you closely notice it will throw
all the result at once. It is not going
to stream. It will take a moment and it
throw all the result. So that is the
difference between front and run stream.
Now let me clear this uh console again.
Now let me go and run it as a stream
here. Same program except that I'm using
a run stream method. Now let me go and
run this particular program here. So now
if you if you see clearly here, it is
you know working as a stream, right?
It's just not as a complete the
execution and throw the output. No, it
doesn't work that way. It's kind of a
stream execution. Just created a
temporary agent. Now we will see how do
we permanently create the agent. So
there are again two ways to create this
agent. First we can use the project
client. I do not know how long this will
support creating creating the agent but
then like there is also going to be
another way. I would assume that that is
going to be continued rather like this
this particular method will get
duplicated in the upcoming releases. So
if you see here we are importing a class
called a project client from this
particular package.
And if I come down here, we are getting
the default credentials. We are
initiating this a project client
by passing the project endpoint
credentials. Now we have this project
client project client. Now what we will
do is that we will use the project
client dot agents.create agent and we
will create a agent. Now we have the
agent. We will pass that agent to the
chat agent. Again know the difference,
right? We just created a agent. We will
pass that particular agent to the chat
agent to make use of the you know
middleware telemetry all this support
right now rest of the program will be
seen but at the end we are also using
the project client dot agents and delete
this now let me go run with six.
So now the agent gets created here. Now
if I just go to the portal here if I do
a refresh I will see that particular
agent. Now what is the llm? Again the
agent will get
get the input and the like it is going
to respond back to us.
Now let me quit. So if I quit so the way
means like basically like the permanent
agents
should stay in the portal but then like
for a demo purposes I don't want to keep
any agents. So that's why like as soon
as I am done I'm deleting I'm requesting
to delete the agent but it's up to you
right if you if you really wanted to
keep this agent in the portal you can
keep it now let me go ahead and clean
this and the agent gets get deleted so
there is a difference right the
temporary agents will automatically get
deleted but the like the permanent agent
I'm asking the project client to delete
that agent and there is also another way
to create the agent and this time around
I use the agents client not the project
client. This is a subset of the project
client. At some point they will combine
everything. They will keep only one
class but the now we can either use the
project client or agent client to create
the agent but like the implementation it
is going to be the same. Get the default
credentials. Initialize the agents
client by passing the project client and
the credentials. Now create a agent
here. pass that agent to the uh chart or
maybe we can also directly use it.
Right? So in this program we are not
passing it to the chart agent rather
like it is directly being used. It's up
to us like we can create the agent and
pass it to the chart agent. If at all
you wanted to have the additional
features that includes the middleware
telemetry all this information right but
if you if you don't need all of these
you can very well just directly use the
agent. That's what how it's done in this
particular program. Then we just pass
the information to the agent. So if you
see here in this particular program, we
are using the thread. But then like I
don't want to cover the thread. Uh I
will come back and discuss about the
thread in a while. But let me go and run
this program Python 7. Right? So okay
now again like we are creating the agent
here. Same question. What is llm? So it
is going to respond back. So now in
between now let me copy this agent uh ID
here to the next program. So in this
program I wanted to use the existing
agent right in in our previous in this
particular program in the seventh
program we just created a agent but in
the eighth program I don't want to
create a new agent rather like I wanted
to utilize the existing agent. So all
you need is the agent ID and the way you
do it it's pretty simple. So Azure a
agent client pass the credentials pass
the project endpoint also pass the agent
ID. If you pass the agent ID and if it
is exist then it is not going to create
a new agent rather like it will use the
existing agent. But if you still pass
the agent ID which is which doesn't
exist then it is going to create a agent
for you call it as a unnamed agent or
something like that. But in our case
like we just created a agent that is
already exist. Now let me go ahead and
run the program here. So that is a
eighth program. Use the existing agent.
Now if I just see what is uh llm.
So here it says that uh connecting to
the agent uh this particular agent
connected successfully. If I go back to
the portal you will not see two
different agent rather like it is going
to be the same agent. Now if I come back
to this seventh program where I created
the agent. If I quit the agent will get
deleted. Now if I go back to the eighth
program and run it, it is going to fail.
The reason is that if I just go to the
portal again, there is not going to be
any agent. I just deleted the agent. I
wanted to delete the agent. I deleted
the agent. It's up to us. Right? Again,
if I just come over here at the end of
the program, I say like a clean up
everything, right? So clean up the
thread, clean up the agent. We will come
back and discuss about thread, right?
So, but then like again, I deleted the
agent also. It's up to me because this
is a permanent agent right. So now let
me quit this uh program also.
So now so far like what we have
discussed is that how do we create a
temporary agent? How do we create the
permanent agent and you know how do we
use all of these agents right? So in the
videos we will continue to discuss the
advanced concept. Thank you for this.